//8 questions here so far
{
	"question": "Which is not a factor to be considered when determining a safe speed",
	"answer": "speed of own vessel over ground",
	"options": [
			"the state of visibility",
			"traffic density",
			"the presence of background light at night",
			"the draught in relation to the available depth",
			"limitations of the radar",
			""
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 6",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "According to the collision regulation, when shall a vessel proceed at safe speed?",
	"answer": "at all times",
	"options": [
			"when the radar is down",
			"when not keeping a look-out",
			"in traffic-dense waters",
			"in narrow channels",
			"in shallow waters"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 6",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "If in doubt about the existence of a risk of collision, such risk shall _______",
	"answer": "be deemed to exist",
	"options": [
			"be re-evaluated",
			"be considered insignificant",
			"be reported to the IMO",
			"be reported to the flag state",
			"be ignored"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 7",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "Complete the statement. 'Assumptions shall not be made on the basis of scanty information, _____'",
	"answer": "especially scanty radar information",
	"options": [
			"especially scanty AIS information",
			"especially scanty meteorological reports",
			"such information shall be ignored",
			"except scanty radar information",
			"except scanty AIS information"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 7 (c)",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "An approaching tanker vessel has a bearing of 147 degrees. 12 minutes later, the tanker vessel has the same bearing. What does this mean?",
	"answer": "a risk of collision exist",
	"options": [
			"the tanker is not underway",
			"own vessel is underway",
			"the tanker is proceeding at safe speed",
			"the tanker is on a constant speed",
			"own vessel is not underway"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 7 (d)",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "According to rule 8 of the regulations, actions taken to avoid collision shall be ",
	"answer": "made in ample time",
	"options": [
			"executed immediately",
			"made only with the captain on bridge",
			"to slacken the speed of own vessel",
			"to alter course immediately",
			"made after a successful ship-to-ship communication"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 8",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "According to the regulations, what shall be large enough to be readily apparent?",
	"answer": "actions to avoid collision",
	"options": [
			"look-out",
			"safe speed",
			"existence of risk of collision",
			"traffic separation schemes",
			"narrow channels"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 9",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "According to the provisions of the rules, can a vessel cross the narrow channel or fairway?",
	"answer": "as long as it does not impede the passage of another",
	"options": [
			"no, no vessel can cross a narrow channel",
			"as long as the vessel is less than 100 metres in length",
			"depends on the laws of the flag states",
			"depends on the laws if the port states",
			"Yes, absolutely",
			"only in cases of emergencies"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 9(d)",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "According to rule 9 of the collision regulations, a vessel in a narrow channel shall keep to her _____",
	"answer": "starboard side",
	"options": [
			"portside",
			"side specified by UNCLOS",
			"windward side",
			"leeward side",
			"preffered side"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 9 (a)",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "What does the collision regulation say about anchoring in a narrow channel?",
	"answer": "avoid it, if the circumstance of the case admit",
	"options": [
			"whatever the case may be, avoid it completely",
			"anchor at your own risk",
			"you would have to pay to anchor",
			"stem the tide before anchoring",
			"request permission from local authorities",
			"only vessels less than 20 metres can anchore in narrow channels"			
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 9 (g)",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "What does rule 10 cover?",
	"answer": "Traffic Separation Schemes",
	"options": [
			"Narrow Channel",
			"Look out",
			"Safe Speed",
			"Action to avoid collision",
			"Sailing vessels"
		],
	"explanation": "Rule 10 talks about traffic separation schemes",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "According to the collision regulations, 'A vessel joining or leaving a traffic lane shall do so at an (X) angle to the general direction of traffic flow as practicable. What is X?'",
	"answer": "small",
	"options": [
			"large",
			"any",
			"right",
			"acute",
			"obtuse",
			"preferred",
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 10 (b) and it should not be confused with rule 10 (c)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "What does the collision regulations say about crossing traffic lanes?",
	"answer": "avoid it as far as practicable",
	"options": [
			"in no situation is it permitted",
			"seek permission of the local authorities",
			"avoid it if own vessel is less than 20 metres",
			"avoid it if the visibility is not clear enough",
			"avoid it if the sea is not calm",
			"avoid it in traffic-dense waters"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 10 (c)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "According to the collision regulations, 'a vessel crossing traffic lanes, shall do so on a heading as practicable at (X) angles to the general direction of traffic flow'. WHat is X?",
	"answer": "right",
	"options": [
			"small",
			"large",
			"any",
			"acute",
			"obtuse"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 10 (c) and must not be confused with rule 10 (b)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "Are vessels engaged in fishing permitted to use the inshore traffic zone?",
	"answer": "Yes, they are",
	"options": [
			"No, they are not",
			"If the circumstance permits",
			"Only if she cannot safely use apprpriate traffic lanes",
			"If she is more than 20 metres in length",
			"The collision regulations is silent on this"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 10 (d)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "According to the collision regulations, when can a (non-crossing) vessel enter a separation zone?",
	"answer": "in emergencies and when fishing",
	"options": [
			"in emergencies only",
			"whenever she feels like",
			"whenever the local authorities permit",
			"whenever she wants to anchor",
			"when the pilot is onboard"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 10 (e)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "What does the collision regulations say about sailing vessels following a traffic lane?",
	"answer": "they should not impede the passage of power-driven vessels",
	"options": [
			"absolutely nothing",
			"they shall not drop anchors",
			"they are not permitted at all to do so",
			"power-driven vessels must keep clear off them",
			"they shall be considered as vessels not under command"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 10 (j)",
	"chapter": 2
}, 
//begining of Day 3 input -> 10 new input added to previous 17 entries
{
	"question": "Two vessels are approaching each other with the possibility of a collision. Sailing vessel A has the wind on her port side. Sailing vessel B has the wind on her starboard side. Which of the vessels, according to rule 12, is the give-way vessel?",
	"answer": "Sailing vessel A because she has the wind on her port side",
	"options": [
			"Sailing Vessel B because she has the wind on her starboard side",
			"Sailing vessel B because she is smaller",
			"Sailing vessel A because she is larger",
			"whichever ship that makes the sound signals first",
			"they both have to communicate and decide"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 12 (a)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "How does rule 12 of the collision regulation explains the 'windward' side of a sailing ship?",
	"answer": "side opposite to that on which the mainsail is carried",
	"options": [
			"side on which the main sail is carried",
			"side adjacent to that which the mainsail is carried",
			"portside of the fore-and-aft sail",
			"starboard of the fore-and-aft sail"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 12 (b)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "According to the collision regulations, a vessel shall be deemed to be overtaking when comming up with another vessel from a direction more than (X) degrees abaft her beam. What is X?",
	"answer": "22.5",
	"options": [
			"45",
			"12.5",
			"25",
			"90",
			"24.5",
			"10 to 11"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 13 (b)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "A vessel in doubt as to whether she is overtaking another shall _____",
	"answer": "assume she is and act accordingly",
	"options": [
			"shall assume she is not and act accordingly",
			"shall asume she is but not act accordingly",
			"shall assume to be a crossing vessel",
			"shall slacken her speed until she is no longer in doubt",
			"shall speed up until she is no longer in doubt",
			"shall be detained by the port authorities"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 13 (c)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "When a container ship is overtaking a LNG carrier. It is the duty of _____ to keep clear off the other ship according to the collision regulations.",
	"answer": "the container ship because she is overtaking the other",
	"options": [
			"the LNG carrier becuase she is the overtaken vessel",
			"the LNG carrier because she is carrying flammable cargo",
			"the container ship because she is larger",
			"the LNG carrier because she is restricted in her ability to manoeuvre"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 13 (d)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "Two vessels on reciprocal or nearly reciprocal courses shall alter course and pass each other on what side?",
	"answer": "the portside",
	"options": [
			"the starboard side",
			"the aft side",
			"the stern side",
			"the windward side",
			"the leeward side"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 14 (a)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "what lights would be seen at night when there is a risk of head-on or nearly head-on situation?",
	"answer": "the mast head light",
	"options": [
			"one side light",
			"no light",
			"the superstructure light",
			"the anchor light",
			"the red mast light"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 14 (b)",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "Your vessel which is a 16000 GT container vessel is in a crossing situation with a tanker ship with a certain risk of collision. Your own vessel can see the other vessel on your starboard. Which is the give way vessel?",
	"answer": "own ship because you have the other on your starboard",
	"options": [
			"the tanker vessel becuase she is on your starboard side",
			"the tanker vessel becuase she is smaller",
			"own vessel because the tanker in restricted in her ability to manoeuvre",
			"you would communicate with the other vessel and figure that out"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 15",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "Action by the give-way vessel is the focus of rule _____.",
	"answer": "16",
	"options": [
			"12",
			"14",
			"18",
			"20",
			"19"
		],
	"explanation": "rule 16 covers action by the give-way vessel",
	"chapter": 2
}, {
	"question": "The collision regulation does not relieve the give-way vessel of her obligation to keep out of the way.",
	"answer": "This is absolutely true",
	"options": [
			"This is absolutely false",
			"This is true for vessels larger than 100 metres",
			"This is false for training vessels",
			"This is true for fishing vessels",
			"This is false in restricted visibility"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 17 (d)",
	"chapter": 2
},
//end of day 3 input with 17 entries
{
	"question": "Considering the responsibility between vessels, which is supposed to keep-out of the way of another: a sailing vessel or a vessel engaged in fishing?",
	"answer": "sailing vessel",
	"options": [
			"fishing vessel",
			"the larger vessel",
			"the vessel under command",
			"the contrained vessel"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 18b and 18c for clarification",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "Are seaplanes required to comply with all the rules the maritime collision regulations when on water?",
	"answer": "yes, where risk of collision exist",
	"options": [
			"no, they have their own rules",
			"just the safe speed rule",
			"yes, but they have no responsibility to other vessels",
			"just the traffic separation schemes and look-out rules"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 18(e)",
	"chapter": 2
},{
	"question": "In restricted visibility, every vessel shall proceed at a safe speed. A power-driven vessel shall _____",
	"answer": "have her engines ready for immediate manoeuvre",
	"options": [
			"have her engines dead slow ahead",
			"have her sound signalling systems ready",
			"have her light signalling systems ready",
			"have her engines stopped",
			"all accomodation lights turned on",
			"all signalling systems ready"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 19(b)",
	"chapter": 2
},
//Day 4 - 8 new entry 5 of which are for the third chapter

{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},